# **MEGAN MCDEVITT**

# **SOFTWARE** DEVELOPER

mcdevittbass@gmail.com

mcdevittbass.github.io/portfolio

**4**15-816-6973

**♀** Greater Buffalo Area (open to move)

in megmcd

• mcdevittbass

Whether I'm developing my double bass or JavaScript skills, I'm always striving to improve. In my 10-year career as a musician and teacher, I have developed the arts of attention to detail, long-term planning, and discipline through selfawareness, creativity, and curiosity.

I am now applying these attributes to the tech world after completing Nucamp's Full Stack Bootcamp with honors. When I'm not building a React app, learning Python, or playing music, you can find me hanging out with my husband and my dog, Ligeti.

### Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: JavaScript,

C, Python, Typescript, PHP, jQuery

WEB DEVELOPMENT: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, React, ReactNative, Redux, NodeJS, React Hooks

TOOLS & DATABASES: Git/Github, Bash, MongoDB, Max/MSP, PostgreSQL

## **Education**

Nucamp Full Stack Bootcamp

Jan. 2020 to June

Certificate with Honors

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, Redux, React Native, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB

University of Michigan DMA Music 2017 Aug. 2014 to Aug. 2017

San Francisco Conservatory of Music

Masters Music 2010

Aug. 2008 to May 2010

University of California, Santa Cruz

Sept. 2003 to **June 2007** 

Bachelors Music 2007

## Awards

Nucamp Coding Bootcamp · lune Certificate of Honor

Completed 5-month coding bootcamp with honors.

# **Projects**

Front End Developer - Greater Chicago Food Depository (group)

This app will work to connect people in Illinois with food needs to federal programs by mapping aggregated data for public policy organizations.

My contributions:

· Incorporate Redux, including modern syntax and async logic using Thunk middleware, to consolidate state management

Review pull requests on GitHub

Participate in weekly stand-ups and additional front end meetings

Discuss best practices and contribute to decision-making

Teck Stack: React, Redux, Mapbox

#### Full Stack Developer - Neutral Zone App (pair)

Aug. 2020 to Current

Dec. 2020 to Current

An interactive app for an online version of restorative circles for a teen center.

- Regularly meet with client to discuss specifications and progress
- Use React to make a responsive, interactive user interface
- Make decisions on how to incorporate backend
- Consult with partner to determine best priorities, debug, and decide on frameworks

Tech Stack: React (Javascript), Konva library, backend TBD

#### Game Developer - Intergalactic Trash Collector (solo)

Aug. 2020 to Sept. 2020

Game made using Phaser JS as part of Mintbean's Hackathon.

- Wrote code in JavaScript to create background, sprites, and responses to keyboard input.
- Troubleshot conflicting information from confusing documentation.
- Deployed using Github pages.

Tech Stack: JS, HTML, Phaser 3 library

#### Front End Developer - Five Points Bakery Site (Solo)

Feb. 2020 to Dec. 2020

New-and-improved website for a Buffalo bakery including modals, forms, carousels, and a beautiful layout. Then, code was refactored from HTML site to ReactIS, creating reusable components to display all of the same features.

- Met with Five Points owners to asses specifications to give them the results they wanted, then followed up.
- Designed and implemented most of the site pages and features in an elegant layout.
- Updated the site to React to maximize efficiency and speed.
- Deployed to Github Pages to show client the product in progress.

Tech Stack: React, SCSS (originally HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JQuery)

#### Contributor - evolution (open source)

July 2020 to Aug. 2020

Open-ended project within a Junior Developer community.

- · Refactored components from html to React and added some styling.
- Submitted a pull request on GitHub, responding to comments quickly and updating code based on specifications.

Tech Stack: HTML, JS, React

# **Employment**

#### Contract Software Development

Buffalo, NY Feb. 2020 to Current

Software Developer

- Design professional quality websites and web apps for local businesses.
- Meet with stakeholders to establish vision & build a prioritized list of features
- Write efficient code and deploy it.
- Meet with stakeholders regularly to review and incorporate feedback.
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React (with Redux and Hooks), React Native, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Git/GitHub

#### **Buffalo String Works**

Buffalo, NY Jan. 2018 to July 2020

Sept. 2017 to Jan. 2018

Managed year-round program planning to ensure processes for efficient/effective operations.

- Managed all program data through Airtable bases, ensuring organized, efficient retrieval of information.
- Designed, created, and distributed monthly newsletters to broader Buffalo String Works community, maintaining brand consistency, to secure donor and community engagement.
- Communicated daily with parents from under-resourced communities, particularly refugee groups.

Site Manager Assured safety and preparation for program of over 50 students.

Sept. 2017 to June 2020 Planned curriculum and taught double bass in groups to students from 4th through 10th grade, giving them mentorship, new skills, and a sense of belonging.

#### Megan McDevitt, Professional Musician

recently with the Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra.

San Francisco, Ann Arbor, Buffalo June 2011 to Aug. 2019

Double Bass Instructor

Planned curriculum, prepared performances, and regularly maintained double bass studios of 4-15 students of middle school and high school age, providing mentorship and new skills, and clear communication with parents.

> San Francisco, Ann Arbor, Buffalo Sept. 2011 to Current

Prepare, rehearse, and perform in many orchestras, chamber groups, new music ensembles, and solo recitals, most